<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

    <properties>
        <title>MapLoadParameter interface</title>
    </properties>

    <body>
        <section name="MapLoadParameter">
            <p>
                The interface MapLoadParameter defines methods for the identification and the
                type of a parameter. Parameters are used by the map loader to e.g. detect the
                location of the map data and/or to identify a region to be loaded. They may
                be required or optional and each parameter has a type. The type is used to present
                a file load dialog, a directory load dialog or a single text field.
            </p>

            <source>
                /**
                * Licensed to the TomTom International B.V. under one
                * or more contributor license agreements. See the NOTICE file
                * distributed with this work for additional information
                * regarding copyright ownership. TomTom International B.V.
                * licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
                * Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
                * in compliance with the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at
                *
                * http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
                *
                * Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
                * software distributed under the License is distributed on an
                * "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
                * KIND, either express or implied. See the License for the
                * specific language governing permissions and limitations
                * under the License.
                */
                /**
                * Copyright (C) 2009-2012 TomTom International B.V.
                *
                * TomTom (Legal Department)
                * Email: legal@tomtom.com
                *
                * TomTom (Technical contact)
                * Email: openlr@tomtom.com
                *
                * Address: TomTom International B.V., Oosterdoksstraat 114, 1011DK Amsterdam,
                * the Netherlands
                */
                package openlr.map.loader;

                import java.io.Serializable;

                /**
                * The interface MapLoadParameter defines methods for the identification and the
                * type of a parameter. Parameters are used by the map loader to e.g. detect the
                * location of the map data and/or to identify a region to be loaded. They may
                * be required or optional and each parameter has a type. The type is used to present
                * a file load dialog, a directory load dialog or a single text field.
                *
                *
                * OpenLR is a trade mark of TomTom International B.V.
                *
                * email: software@openlr.org
                *
                * @author TomTom International B.V.
                */
                public interface MapLoadParameter extends Serializable {

                /**
                * The enum ParameterType defines the type of a parameter. The type is used to
                * show a file or directory dialog or a single textfield in the map load parameter
                * dialog.
                */
                public enum ParameterType {

                /** The FILE. */
                FILE,

                /** The DIRECTORY. */
                DIRECTORY,

                /** The STRING. */
                STRING;
                }

                /**
                * Gets the type of the parameter. This type decides whether a file/directory
                * load dialog or a single text field will be used in the map load parameter
                * dialog.
                *
                * @return the parameter type
                */
                ParameterType getType();

                /**
                * Gets the name of the parameter. This name will be used as a label in the
                * map load parameter dialog and should be unique.
                *
                * @return the name
                */
                String getName();

                /**
                * Checks if this parameter is required.
                *
                * @return true, if the parameter is required
                */
                boolean isRequired();

                /**
                * Return the description of the parameter. This description will be used as
                * a tooltip in the map load parameter dialog.
                *
                * @return the description
                */
                String getDescription();

                /**
                * Gets the identifier which uniquely identifies this parameter for a specific map loader.
                *
                * @return the identifier
                */
                int getIdentifier();

                /**
                * Gets the value of the parameter. If the value is not set the method shall return null.
                *
                * @return the value
                */
                String getValue();

                /**
                * Sets the value of the parameter.
                *
                * @param val the new value
                */
                void setValue(String val);

                }
            </source>

        </section>


    </body>

</document>