<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

    <properties>
        <title>Map load interface</title>
    </properties>

    <body>
        <section name="Map load interface">
            <a name="_top"/>
            <p>
                The map load interface package defines methods which needs to be implemented
                in order to provide a new map to be shown in the MapViewer. The map loader
                implementation is aware of the underlying layout of the map data and makes
                this data available through this map loader interface and the OpenLR map interface.
            </p>
            <p>
                An implementation of the map loader interface needs to be registered as a service
                so that the MapViewer is able to use it during runtime. The implementation needs
                to be in the class path and will be found at runtime automatically. All required
                classes must be packaged into a jar-file including a file named
            </p>
            <p>
                META-INF/services/openlr.map.loader.OpenLRMapLoader
            </p>
            <p>
                The content of this text file is the fully qualified name of the map loader
                interface implementation.
            </p>
            <p>
                The parameters used to load a map are defined in the interface MapLoadParameter. It
                defines methods for the identification and the
                type of a parameter. Parameters are used by the map loader to e.g. detect the
                location of the map data and/or to identify a region to be loaded. They may
                be required or optional and each parameter has a type. The type is used to present
                a file load dialog, a directory load dialog or a single text field.
            </p>
            <p>
                The following interfaces are defined:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>OpenLRMapLoader</li>
                <li>MapLoadParameter</li>
                <li>OpenLRMapLoaderException</li>
            </ul>

        </section>

    </body>

</document>